

Mohamed Younis Abdallah

• Work: Dubai, UAE., 00000, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Email: mohamedyounis150@gmail.com Phone: (+971) 569802585

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mohamed-abdallah- 254a10199

Gender: Male Date of birth: 25/02/1992 Nationality: Sudanese

ABOUT ME

I am a web developer with 4 years experience and a strong focus on front-end development(React JS), excels in designing and implementing scalable and reliable web applications.

with extensive experience in developing RESTFUL -GraphQL APIs, Full Stack applications, and designing databases.

In deployment and monitoring, I have experience on the Google cloud platform and utilizing technologies such as cloud functions, cloud runs, virtual machines, cloud SQL, big query, and cloud CDN.

In addition, I have strong knowledge about writing designing documents for new products and keeping up-to-date with new technologies.

Finally, I have strong knowledge of data analyest tools like Microsoft power BI and Azure.

DIGITAL SKILLS

javaScript | React.js / Vue.js | Jquery | Node.js | Express js | REST APIs | GraphQL |
Testing/Debugging | Azure Web Services | Go (Programming Language) | ES5 - ES6 |
HTML/HTML5/CSS | Bootstrap 4 & 5 | Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL,
PostgreSQL | Mango DB | CI /CD | agile method | Git | Object-Oriented Programming
(OOP) | C and C++ | Java | Statistical Data Analysis | Python (Programming Language)
| Microsoft Power BI | Analytical Skills | Learn New Software Quickly

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/09/2021 - 01/04/2022]

Back End developer

ISAP Soluations

City: Dubai

Country: United Arab Emirates

- Analyzed user requirements and designed efficient back-end solutions.
- Programmed and implemented web applications, ensuring optimal functionality.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to troubleshoot and resolve issues promptly.
- Contributed to database design, optimizing data storage and retrieval.
- Actively participated in code reviews, providing valuable feedback.
- Proactively identified and implemented system improvements, meeting project milestones.

[01/01/2020 - 01/01/2021]

Front End developer

Almassar charity Organization

City: Kosti

Country: Sudan

- Designed impactful donation websites for Almassar Charity, Kosti, Sudan, focusing on refugee support.
- Collaborated on user-friendly interfaces using React JS for dynamic and responsive web experiences.
- Conducted usability tests and ensured cross-browser compatibility.
- Worked closely with back-end developers and contributed to coding standards.
- Stayed updated on industry trends to enhance design projects.

[01/01/2021 - 01/08/2021]

Database administrator

Almassar Charity Organization

City: Kosti

Country: Sudan

- Orchestrated database creation and organization at Almassar Charity, Sudan.
- Analyzed data, extracting insights crucial for informed decision-making.
- Generated reports to communicate findings, supporting strategic initiatives.
- Ensured data integrity, collaborated on efficient data management processes.

[01/03/2019 – 01/12/2019] **Front End developer**

Enigma

City: Khartoum Country: Sudan

- Drove React JS development at Enigma, Khartoum.
- Translated requirements into dynamic web interfaces for optimal user experience.
- Collaborated on seamless integration and maintained coding standards.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and contributed to project planning.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[12/2020]

Bachelor (HONORS) in Mathematics and Computer Science.

University Of Khartoum www.uofk.edu

City: Khartoum Country: Sudan

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Arabic

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

PROJECTS

[30/01/2020 - Current] **T2meen webSite (2020 - Present)**

Link: https://t2meen.com/

[06/2020 - Current] **Mahmall**

Link: https://ae.mahmall.com/ar

COURSES

[01/12/2015 - 01/01/2016] **CCNA Certificate.**

[25/05/2021 - 16/06/2021] **Electronic Accounting**

Electronic Accounting content on (Excel Advance, QuickBooks and Odoo)